Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College
Items in this collection do not circulate and may be used in-house only.
- Lowell Thomas Papers, Marist Archives and Special Collections 3399 North Road, Poughkeepsie, New York 12601; Lowell Thomas; 2.1.1.2.1.1
  - Graphic Material, 2
    - Photographs, 2.1
      - Glass plate negatives, 2.1.1.
        - Lowell Thomas, 2.1.1.2
          - Indexed Photographs, 2.1.1.2.1
            - Arabia, 2.1.1.2.1.1
                - Arabian “Hindu” bathing on deck of S.S. Ozarda, 1918; 1 (Box 1262)
                4x5
                - Sheep on board deck of S.S. Ozarda [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Our fellow passengers crossing the Red Sea], 1918; 2
                film
                - Wadi Araba, caravan in distance, 1918; 3
                - Wadi Araba, caravan, close-up, 1918; 4
                - Caravan in Wadi Araba, Lowell Thomas on camel in foreground with back to camera, 1918; 5
                - Camel caravan in Wadi Araba, Lowell Thomas on camel in foreground [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A camel caravan in the Wadi Araba], 1918; 6
                - British soldiers in automobile talking to Bedouins, 1918; 7
                - Abdullah with camel train, 1918; 8
                - Gueira camp, close-up, 1918; 9
                - Arab prison camp, guard with rifle in foreground, 1918; 10
                - Emir Feisal and T. E. Lawrence holding morning audience outdoors in front of tents, distant view, 1918; 11
                - Bedouin department store, outdoor gathering, automobile in foreground, 1918; 12
                - Camel’s head, 1918; 13
                - Airplane at Akaba, two men in cockpits, 1918; 14
                - Arab horsemen charging up shore, 1918; 15
                - Masts of ships at Jedda, 1918; 16
                - Jedda panorama from housetop, 1918; 17
                - British headquarters in Jedda, 1918; 18
                - Street scene in Jedda, 1918; 19
                - Eve’s Tomb, Jedda [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The last resting-place of the Mother of us all], 1918; 20
                - Large hotel, Jedda [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The Waldorf-Astoria of Arabia-including 200 rooms with accommodations for 1000 guests with all the latest Arabian conveniences excepting bath, ‘phone, light, heat, or service], 1918; 21
                - T. E. Lawrence standing, three quarter length [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The archeologist and poet who turned soldier], 1918; 22
                5x7
                - T. E. Lawrence standing, three quarter length [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The archeologist and poet who turned soldier], 1918; 23
                - T. E. Lawrence standing on balcony in Arab robe and headdress, full figure [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The “Uncrowned King” of the Arabs on the Governor’s balcony in Jerusalem], 1918; 24
                - T. E. Lawrence standing outdoors on a prayer rug [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence in front of his headquarters tent], 1918; 25
                - T. E. Lawrence standing outdoors on a prayer rug [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence in front of his headquarters tent], 1918; 26
                - T. E. Lawrence, D. G. Hogarth, Allan Dawnay, full figure [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel Lawrence conferring with Commander D. G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau in Cairo, 1918; 27
                - T. E. Lawrence, D. G. Hogarth, full figure, Allan Dawnay cropped out of photograph [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel Lawrence conferring with Commander D. G. Hogarth, one of his advisers at the Arab Bureau in Cairo, 1918; 28
                - T. E. Lawrence, D. G. Hogarth, Allan Dawnay, close-up, 1918; 29
                - T. E. Lawrence in British uniform, grinning, three quarter figure [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence at headquarters in Cairo], 1918; 30
                - T. E. Lawrence in British uniform, full figure, 1918; 31
                - T. E. Lawrence in British uniform, full figure [copy, cropped], 1918; 32
                - T. E. Lawrence and his bodyguard in the desert [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Sidi” Lawrence and his “Sons”], 1918; 33
                - T. E. Lawrence and his bodyguard in the desert [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Sidi” Lawrence and his “Sons”], 1918; 34
                - T. E. Lawrence and two Syrian advisors [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence confers with Arab Nationalists leaders from Bagdad and Damascus], 1918; 35
                - T. E. Lawrence and six of his British staff in front of tent [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: T. E. Lawrence in chair surrounded by members of his British staff], 1918; 36
                - T. E. Lawrence and six of his British staff in front of tent [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: T. E. Lawrence in chair surrounded by members of his British staff], 1918; 37
                - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, ends of headdress back over shoulders, hands clasped, sword at waist, three quarter length [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: In his white robes Lawrence looked like a prophet], circa 1918 - 1921; 38
                - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe, squatting, full-faced, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Col. T. E. Lawrence], circa 1918 - 1921; 39
                - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe, squatting, full-faced, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Col. T. E. Lawrence], circa 1918 - 1921; 40
                - T. E. Lawrence sitting on floor, toe of boot showing, circa 1918 - 1921; 41
                - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, three quarter side view, left hand on sword [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The King-maker], circa 1918 - 1921; 42
                - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, three quarters side view, left hand on sword [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The King-maker], circa 1918 - 1921; 43
                - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, three quarters front, hands behind back, headdress over shoulders, sword at waist, circa 1918 - 1921; 44
                - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe, three quarter view, both hands on sword, full-faced [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel T. E. Lawrence, the mystery man of Arabia], circa 1918 - 1921; 45
                - T. E. Lawrence in white robe, three quarter view, full-faced, head cloth hanging down [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Shereef” Lawrence], circa 1918-1921; 46
                - T. E. Lawrence in white, three quarter side view, hands clasped over knee, circa 1918-1921; 47
                - T. E. Lawrence in white robe with sword at waist, sitting on floor, side view, right hand on chin [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The dreamer whose dreams came true], circa 1918-1921; 48
                - T. E. Lawrence in white, three quarter view, sitting on stool, sword at waist, circa 1918-1921; 49
                - T. E. Lawrence in paisley robe, side view, holding book, sword at waist (Graphlex), circa 1918-1921; 50
                - T. E. Lawrence, full length, white robe, sword at waist (Graphlex), circa 1918-1921; 51
                - T. E. Lawrence, full length, white robe, sword at waist (Graphlex), circa 1918-1921; 52
                - Colonel P. C. Joyce, second in command to T. E. Lawrence [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Colonel Joyce, Commander of the Arab “Regulars”], 1918; 53
                - Hussein Ibn Ali, King of the Hedjaz [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: King of the Hejaz, “Commander of the Faithful,” and founder of a new Arabian dynasty], 1918; 54
                - Hussein Ibn Ali, King of the Hedjaz [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: King of the Hejaz, “Commander of the Faithful,” and founder of a new Arabian dynasty], 1918; 55
                3.5x 4.5
                - Emir Feisal [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Emir Feisal, now King of Mesopotamia (Irak)], 1918; 1 (Box 1263)
                - His Royal Highness Emir Feisal, 1918; 2
                - T. E. Lawrence and Emir Feisal at right conferring with Bedouin sheiks [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Feisal and Lawrence conferring with Bedouin Sheiks], 1918; 3
                - T. E. Lawrence and Emir Feisal conferring with Bedouin sheiks, 1918; 4
                - Auda Abu Tayi, center, and two brothers [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Sheik Auda Abu Tayi, the Bedouin Robin Hood], 1918; 5
                - Emir Feisal on horse, 1918; 6
                - Mounted Bedouins [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Bedouin “Irregulars” ready for a raid on the Turks], 1918; 7
                - Scottish soldiers talking to Arabs, Akaba, 1918; 8
                - Arab and Egyptian guards sitting in front of hut at an oasis, 1918; 9
                - Bedouin with curls [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A brigand from Jebel Druz], 1918; 10
                - Arab man [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A Sheik of Araby], 1918; 11
                - Bedouin sheik on horse [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Tallal El-Hareidhin of Tafas], 1918; 12
                - Bedouin with curls holding rifle [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: An Arab Apollo], 1918; 13
                - Druses from Hauran [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Druses from the Hauran], 1918; 14
                - Crowd of Bedouins squatting and standing, Solomon’s Mountains in background, 1918; 15
                - Bedouin barber shop at an oasis, 1918; 16
                - Scottish soldiers and Arabs at Akaba, 1918; 17
                - Head of Gulf of Akaba from shore, two ships in distance, 1918; 18
                - British cruiser off Arabian coast, man in foreground, 1918; 19
                - Akaba waterfront [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Shore-line at the head of the Gulf of Akaba], 1918; 20
                - Akaba waterfront [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Shore-line at the head of the Gulf of Akaba], 1918; 21
                - Akaba, looking down from housetop, ship in distance, 1918; 22
                - Women carrying fuel on shore of Akaba, 1918; 23
                - Squatting Bedouins, close-up, with camels at Akaba, 1918; 24
                - Mazuk, vain Bedouin on Emir Feisal’s staff, 1918; 25
                - Distant view of camp beneath cliff at Gueira, men standing in left foreground, 1918; 26
                5x5.75
                - Arab store, horse eating in foreground, Lowell Thomas at right, 1918; 27
                - Abyssinian followers of Emir Feisal, 1918; 28
                - Malud Bey and Arab cavalry leaders, 1918; 29
                - Bedouin snipers, 1918; 30
                - Arab cavalry under Malud Bey [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Malud Bey and his Arab cavalry], 1918; 31
                - Dinner party, left to right: Nuri Pasha, Auda Abu Tayi, Emir Feisal, Lowell Thomas, 1918; 32
                - Bedouin camp among old Turkish trenches, 1918; 33
                - Emir Feisal and Lowell Thomas using field glasses to watch a battle at Maan, 1918; 34
                - Arab regular army drawn up at foot of hill, 1918; 35
                - Three armored cars in silhouette at sunset [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Armored cars in holy Arabia], 1918; 36
                - Armored cars and motor trucks in front of tents at Gueira, 1918; 37
                - Arab battery in action, sunset, fighting near Damascus [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lawrence’s mountain guns in action], 1918; 38
                - Arab battery, not firing, 1918; 39
                - Harry Chase taking motion pictures from armored car [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Mr. Chase opening fire with his cinema camera from the turret of an armored car], 1918; 40
                - Bedouin cavalry and British armored cars in desert, Lowell Thomas seated at center, 1918; 41
                - General Nuri Pasha with staff and flag, 1918; 42
                - Lone Bedouin sentinel above Negib [Negev?], 1918; 43
                - Automobile in wildest Arabia, [Lowell Thomas? with back to camera seated on hood of the auto], 1918; 44
                - General Nuri Pasha and staff greeting Lowell Thomas [Lowell Thomas fourth from left], 1918; 1 (Box 1264)
                - Squadron of armored cars in front of cliff, 1918; 2
                - Five Bedouin horsemen, 1918; 3
                - Mountains of Edom near Petra, Lowell Thomas’s caravan in foreground [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Our caravan approaching the “Lost City”], 1918; 4
                - Mountains of Edom, sunset, Bedouin in foreground, 1918; 5
                - Mountains of Edom, sunset [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Sunset over the mountain of Edom], 1918; 6
                - Mountains of Edom, sunset, near view, 1918; 7
                - Valley twelve miles wide running toward Petra, 1918; 8
                - Arab officer on horse at Fountain of Moses, 1918; 9
                - Lowell Thomas having tea at Wadi Musa, 1918; 10
                - A Bedouin sheik, 1918; 11
                - Old Bedouin with pipe, 1918; 12
                - Wadi Musa Bedouins, 1918; 13
                - Roman soldiers’ tomb [Lowell Thomas? with back to camera seated on rock] [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “The tomb of the Roman soldiers”], 1918; 14
                - Temple of Urn, Petra, 1918; 15
                - Temple of Isis (The Deir) from gorge, Arab in foreground, Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A rose-red temple carved like a cameo from the face of the mountain, 1918; 16
                - Temple of Isis (The Deir) from gorge, Petra, 1918; 17
                - Temple of Isis (The Deir), Lowell Thomas and others at foot of columns, Petra, 1918; 18
                - Temple of Isis (The Deir), looking out through columns from one side, soldiers in foreground, Petra, 1918; 19
                - Temple of Isis (The Deir), close-up of three columns, Petra, 1918; 20
                - In gorge approaching Petra, man sitting in foreground, 1918; 21
                - Temple of Isis (The Deir), camels among columns, Petra [Lowell Thomas? seated on camel at left], 1918; 22
                - Lowell Thomas on camel under column at the Temple of Isis (The Deir), Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: We rode into the Auditorium on our camels], 1918; 23
                - Temple of Isis (The Deir), bushes in foreground, Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Pharaoh’s Temple” or the “Temple of Isis”], 1918; 24
                - Lowell Thomas drinking in a gorge near Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The narrow defile that leads to the “Lost City”], 1918; 25
                - Man on camel in gorge near Petra, 1918; 26
                - Harry Chase in front of tent, Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Chase reads the Koran while Mohammed in the background takes aim at a circling hawk], 1918; 27
                - Harry Chase in front of tent, Petra [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Chase reads the Koran while Mohammed in the background takes aim at a circling hawk], 1918; 28
                - Lowell Thomas taking notes in front of tent, Petra, 1918; 29
                - Unfinished temples, Petra, man in foreground, 1918; 30
                - Amphitheatre [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: An amphitheatre hewn out of the mountain], 1918; 31
                - Small hill covered with temples, man in foreground, 1918; 32
                - Side view, amphitheatre and valley, Petra, 1918; 33
                - Face in cliff, Petra, 1918; 34
                - Temple at end of bridge, distant, Petra, 1918; 35
                - Temple at end of bridge, close-up, Temple of Urn, Petra, 1918; 36
                - Governor’s tomb, soldier in foreground, Petra, 1918; 37
                - Three men lying among flowers [Lowell Thomas on right], Petra, 1918; 38
                - Phallic monolith, Petra, 1918; 39
                - Lowell Thomas watches as Arabs play tag around phallic monolith, Petra, 1918; 40
                - Mount Hor, three men in foreground, Petra, 1918; 41
                - “Acropolis hills” Petra, 1918; 42
                - Arabs standing in front of tombs near camp, Petra, Lowell Thomas seated on left, 1918; 43
                - Three-storied temple [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The “Three-storied temple”], 1918; 44
                - Holy Mosque, summit of Mount Hor, Lowell Thomas in foreground, Petra, 1918; 1 (Box 1265)
                - Tomb discovered by accident, Petra, 1918; 2
                - Rock waves [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The rock seemed to swirl like watered silk], 1918; 3
                - Structure of rock, Petra, 1918; 4
                - Bedouin women and children, 1918; 5
                - Bedouin family living in Petra Palace, 1918; 6
                - Goat’s hair curtain in a modern Bedouin Petra Palace home, 1918; 7
                - Two Arab men with pistols [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Drinkers of the milk of war”], 1918; 8
                - Two Arab men with pistols [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: “Drinkers of the milk of war”], 1918; 9
                - The Kaaba, Mecca, crowd, fort in distance [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The mosque of the holy Kaaba], 1918; 10
                - The Kaaba, Mecca, crowd, fort in distance (copy), 1918; 11
                - The Kaaba, Mecca, close-up (copy from book), 1918; 12
                - The Haram, Sacred Mosque, Mecca (copy from book), 1918; 13
                - Mecca, panorama of city (copy from book), 1918; 14
                - Medina (copy from book), 1918; 15
                - Medina (copy from book), 1918; 16
                - Medina, part of Mosque of Prophet (copy from book), 1918; 17
                - Mudarwa explosion, 1918; 18
                - Small dynamited bridge [image quality very poor], 1918; 19
                - Dynamited steel bridge, Hedjaz Railway [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: One of the many bridges blown up by Lawrence’s “tulips.”], 1918; 20
                - Three Arab men, full length, front view, 1918; 21
                - Arab crossing railway tracks, 1918; 22
                - Arab man on railway platform, full view, 1918; 23
                - Lieutenant McCall McCowen dressed as Arab, 1918; 24
                - General Edmund Allenby and Emir Feisal [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Field-Marshall Viscount Allenby of Jerusalem and King Feisal of Bagdad], 1918; 25
                - Emir Feisal, T. E. Lawrence and group at Paris [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Emir Feisal, center, with General Nuri to the left and Colonel Lawrence to the right; Captain Pisani of the French mission standing directly behind the Emir, 1919; 26
                - Sunset, Red Sea, silhouette of caravan, 1918; 27
                - Two leaning palms, sea at sunset [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Sunset in the land of the Arabian knights], 1918; 28
                - Panorama of Akaba [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Panorama of Akaba], 1918; 29
                - Panorama of a Bedouin encampment at Akaba [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: A Bedouin encampment], 1918; 30
                - Palm trees, man carrying two buckets [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Where the hosts of Israel are said to have terminated the passage of the Red Sea], 1918; 31
                - Palm trees, sea, sunset, silhouette of man [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Date-palms along the coral shore of Araby], 1918; 32
                - Emir Ali, 1918; 33
                - General Jafaar Pasha from Baghdad [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: General Jafaar Pasha from Bagdad], 1918; 34
                - General Jafaar Pasha from Baghdad [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: General Jafaar Pasha from Bagdad], 1918; 35
                - Colonel S. F. Newcombe, circa 1918; 36
                2.5x5
                - Street scene, men with camels, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 37
                - Street scene, man with camel, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 38
                - Street scene, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 39
                - Street scene, man with camel, little children, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 40
                - Street scene, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 41
                - Mosque, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 42
                - Men standing outside mosque, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 43
                - Girl wearing veils over head and face, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 44
                - Man writing in book, woman standing beside him, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 45
                3.5x4.75
                - Two men standing next to fence, talking, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 46
                - Group of men in Arab dress, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 47
                - Group of men, man on horse in foreground, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 48
                - Two automobiles on road through mountains, people standing outside first automobile, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 49
                - People in Arab headdresses nearby a truck, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 50
                - Man smoking pipe, cacti, building in distance, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 51
                - Soldiers on horses in front of fort, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 52
                - Street scene, people with bundles on heads, Arabia[?], circa 1918; 53